<TEI.2 id="jrc32005D0029-en" n="32005D0029" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32005D0029 English</title>
        <title>2005/29/EC: Commission Decision of 17 January 2005 amending Decision 92/452/EEC as regards embryo collection teams in the United States of America (notified under document number C(2005) 32)Text with EEA relevance</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>32 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32005D0029:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32005D0029:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32005D0029-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">2005/29/EC: Commission Decision of 17 January 2005 amending Decision 92/452/EEC as regards embryo collection teams in the United States of America (notified under document number C(2005) 32)Text with EEA relevance</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Decision</p>
      <p n="3">of 17 January 2005</p>
      <p n="4">amending Decision 92/452/EEC as regards embryo collection teams in the United States of America</p>
      <p n="5">(notified under document number C(2005) 32)</p>
      <p n="6">(Text with EEA relevance)</p>
      <p n="7">(2005/29/EC)</p>
      <p n="8">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to Council Directive 89/556/EEC of 25 September 1989 on animal health conditions governing intra-Community trade in and importation from third countries of embryos of domestic animals of the bovine species [1], and in particular Article 8 thereof,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="12">(1) Commission Decision 92/452/EEC of 30 July 1992 establishing lists of embryo collection teams and embryo production teams approved in third countries for export of bovine embryos to the Community [2] provides that Member States are only to import embryos from third countries where they have been collected, processed and stored by embryo collection teams listed in that Decision.</p>
      <p n="13">(2) The United States of America has requested that an amendment be made to the list as regards entries for that country.</p>
      <p n="14">(3) The United States of America has provided guarantees regarding compliance with the appropriate rules set out in Directive 89/556/EEC and the embryo collection team concerned has been officially approved for exports to the Community by the veterinary services of that country.</p>
      <p n="15">(4) Decision 92/452/EEC should therefore be amended accordingly.</p>
      <p n="16">(5) The measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on the Food Chain and Animal Health,</p>
      <p n="17">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="18">Article 1</p>
      <p n="19">The Annex to Decision 92/452/EEC is amended in accordance with the Annex to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="20">Article 2</p>
      <p n="21">This Decision shall apply from 22 January 2005.</p>
      <p n="22">Article 3</p>
      <p n="23">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="24">Done at Brussels, 17 January 2005.</p>
      <p n="25">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="26">Markos Kyprianou</p>
      <p n="27">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="28">--------------------------------------------------</p>
      <p n="29">[1] OJ L 302, 19.10.1989, p. 1. Directive as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 806/2003 (OJ L 122, 16.5.2003, p. 1).</p>
      <p n="30">[2] OJ L 250, 29.8.1992, p. 40. Decision as last amended by Decision 2004/568/EC (OJ L 252, 28.7.2004, p. 5).</p>
      <p n="31">--------------------------------------------------</p>
      <p n="32">+++++ ANNEX 1 +++++</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
